Contact

todd.rebner@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/toddrebner (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Enterprise Software Executive Leadership Consulting

Honors-Awards
Oracle ACE

Publications

10 Signs It's Time To Cut Losses And End A Tech Project

15 Team-Building Tips For Tech Leaders

13 Expert-Recommended Ways To Automate Your Tech Team's Workflow

Tech Pros Share Tips To Help New Programmers Avoid Common Rookie Mistakes

15 Things Consumer Data Can Do For A Company

Todd Rebner

CTO | Forbes Tech Council Member

Marco Island, Florida

Summary

Todd has over 25 years of professional experience and holds a MBA in Information & Decision Systems from The Weatherhead School of Management @ Case Western Reserve University. He founded and sold a nationally recognized enterprise performance management consulting firm. Todd has worked directly with over 150 companies and managed over 200 projects across 12 industries. He is a member of the Forbes Technology Council and a published author on artificial intelligence with the upcoming book, Absolute AI.

Todd has 15+ years of hands-on experience building data products and supporting analytics solutions (Perl, Python, SQL Server, Hadoop, Hive, Spark, Azure ML Studio, TensorFlow, Essbase, Tableau, Snowflake, SAS). He has directly helped shape the overall enterprise architecture, application security, data governance, and business intelligence landscapes for dozens of Fortune 500 companies. Finally, Todd has developed sophisticated financial reporting, budgeting & forecasting, and advanced analytical solutions for companies nationwide.

Companies he has worked with include: GE, Amazon, Lowes, Boeing, American Apparel, Estee Lauder, Hanover Insurance, Equifax, Humana, JPMorgan Chase, KeyBank, Bank of The West, Wyndham Hotels, Siemens, PNC Bank, Chiquita, Carter's, Navy Federal Credit Union, Erie Insurance, Fossil, Cardinal Health, Office Depot, ADT, Krispy Kreme, Bank of New York Mellon, Cadence Bank, Rag-n-Bone, Honda of America, Pfizer, Fifth Third Bank, John Deere, Equifax, Berkshire Hathaway Automotive, Pfizer, CA Technologies, Oxbow Carbon, Goodyear, and more.

Experience

Forbes Technology Council Official Member & Contributor January 2019 - Present

Marco Island, Florida

Forbes Technology Council is an invitation-only organization comprised of elite CIOs, CTOs and technology executives. My areas of expertise are information technology, machine learning, data science, and quantitative finance.

Cyleron, Inc.
Chief Technology Officer
January 2018 - Present
Marco Island, Florida

Cyleron is a data science and machine learning enabled solutions company. My efforts focus on managing software development and providing data science & advanced analytical advisory services. Supervised the design and development of the CyleronCentry software product and facilitated the sale of the intellectual property and codebase.

Datavail

Vice President & Oracle ACE March 2017 - December 2017 (10 months)

Broomfield, Colorado

Datavail acquired my company, AdvancedEPM Consulting, Inc. I led the global enterprise performance management practice and managed complex business intelligence, data integration, data governance, financial close & consolidation, budgeting & forecasting, and infrastructure engagements.

AdvancedEPM Consulting, Inc.
Founder & CEO
September 2007 - March 2017 (9 years 7 months)
Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

Founded and sold a multimillion dollar consulting firm specialized in the areas of data governance, business intelligence, advanced analytics, financial close & consolidation, budgeting & forecasting, system infrastructure and managed services. Delivered complete and comprehensive advisory, full lifecycle solution implementation, software development, and system support services to over 130 companies. Oracle Platinum Partner for 8 years with 16 specializations.

Whittman-Hart
Managing Consultant
February 2005 - September 2007 (2 years 8 months)
Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

Consulted with over 20 companies whereby I designed & developed business performance management solutions for the office of the CFO. The company was ranked as the #1 North American solution implementation firm by Hyperion Solutions, now Oracle. My primary focus was the design and development of advanced analytical solutions.

National City Bank
Director of Financial Systems
August 2001 - February 2005 (3 years 7 months)
Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

National City Corporation was acquired by PNC. I designed, developed, and deployed information technology solutions for the Office of the CFO, and worked with over 600 end-users as well as dozens of senior management leaders within every banking vertical.

KeyBank Senior Financial Analyst January 1996 - July 2001 (5 years 7 months) Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

Responsible for various aspects of the accounting, budgeting and forecasting, and financial reporting of the Retail Bank, Insurance Management Group, and other LOB's within the company. Developed various advanced analytical solutions for senior management.

Education

Case Western Reserve University - Weatherhead School of Management

MBA, Information & Decision Systems · (2001 - 2005)

Kent State University

Bachelor of Business Administration, Finance/Accounting (1994 - 1996)

Bowling Green State University N/A, Computer Science · (1990 - 1992)